<snoopy id='Homo_sapiens300604'>
<dataquality>A</dataquality>
<openstatus>+</openstatus>
<lastupdate>2011-12-01</lastupdate>
<blindnote>
Pseudouridylation of U3832 is also guided by SNORA8. 
2009年6月18日（山元）snoRNABaseより。Homo sapiens E2 snoRNA. This H/ACA box snoRNA was cloned by Ruff et al. (1993). Psoralen cross-linking experiments showed that E2 interacts with human pre-rRNA within residues 3282 to 3667 of the 28S rRNA sequence (Rimoldi et al. 1993). E2 RNA degradation of frog oocytes shut down production of 18S rRNA and 36S pre-rRNA, suggesting that E2 snoRNA is involved in rRNA processing at the 3' end of 18S RNA (site 2) (Mishra and Eliceiri, 1997). Ganot et al. (1997a) recognised its hairpin-hinge-hairpin-tail structure characteristic of H/ACA box snRNAs. The role of E2 in guiding pseudouridylation of residues U3830 and U3832 in 28S rRNA was evidenced by Ganot et al. (1997b). The pseudouridylation of these residues was previously reported by Ofengand and Bakin (1997). The snoRNAs E2 and ACA6 share the same host gene (LAMR1).
(20100624末安)snoRNABaseを参考にsequenceを3'側から1nt増やした,NCBIを参考にaccession Noを加えた,UCSCを参考にgenomic positionを変更した,evidenceはsnoRNAbaseのレファレンスから抜粋。

(20111201吉浜)ホスト遺伝子の塩基配列と構造をRPGを参考に変更しました。
</blindnote>
<organism>Homo_sapiens</organism>
<gene_name>SNORA62</gene_name>
<family_name>SNORA62</family_name>
<alias>E2</alias>
<family_base>Homo_sapiens</family_base>
<chrom_or_contig>3</chrom_or_contig>
<genome_position>39452545..39452698</genome_position>
<strand>+</strand>
<box type='c'></box>
<box type='d'></box>
<box type='h'>73..78</box>
<box type='aca'>148..150</box>
<host_id>Homo_sapiens100427</host_id>
<host_gene>RPSA</host_gene>
<host_intron></host_intron>
<host_position>5335..5488</host_position>
<organization>Intronic</organization>
<mod_type>H/ACA</mod_type>
<mod_rna>28S rRNA</mod_rna>
<mod_site>28S:U3830,28S:U3832</mod_site>
<duplex_region>28S|9..16|3839..3832|,28S|59..66|3829..3822|,28S|88..94|3841..3835|,28S|131..135|3831..3827|</duplex_region>
<accession>L07383 NT_022517</accession>
<evidence>Ganot, P., Bortolin, M. L., and Kiss, T. (1997a). Site-specific pseudouridine formation in preribosomal RNA is guided by small nucleolar RNAs. Cell 89, 799-809, Ofengand, J., and Bakin, A. (1997). Mapping to nucleotide resolution of pseudouridine residues in large subunit ribosomal RNAs from representative eukaryotes, prokaryotes, archaebacteria, mitochondria and chloroplasts. J Mol Biol 266, 246-268, Ruff, E. A., Rimoldi, O. J., Raghu, B., and Eliceiri, G. L. (1993). Three small nucleolar RNAs of unique nucleotide sequences. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 90, 635-638, Rimoldi, O. J., Raghu, B., Nag, M. K., and Eliceiri, G. L. (1993). Three new small nucleolar RNAs that are psoralen cross-linked in vivo to unique regions of pre-rRNA. Mol Cell Biol 13, 4382-4390, Ganot, P., Caizergues-Ferrer, M., and Kiss, T. (1997b). The family of box ACA small nucleolar RNAs is defined by an evolutionarily conserved secondary structure and ubiquitous sequence elements essential for RNA accumulation. Genes Dev 11, 941-956, Mishra, R. K., and Eliceiri, G. L. (1997). Three small nucleolar RNAs that are involved in ribosomal RNA precursor processing. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A, 94, 4972-4977.</evidence>
<note></note>
<sequence>
TGTGCACATTGTTAGAGCTTGGAGTTGAGGCTACTGACTGGCCGATGAACTCGCAAGTGT
AGGTAGTGTGCTACATGAGGGGCAAGTTTTCGCTAACACCACAAGGGTCTCTGGCCCAAT
GAGTGGAGTTTGATAGTAATTCTTGCTACAAGTA
</sequence>
</snoopy>
